Yes. So a friend of
mine, who has all his
life been a passionate fan
of music, and when he made some money,
he built himself a dedicated music
room with a fancy stereo,
and it's lined with CDs,
and now he's going back and
buying vinyl, and he's playing all that.
And he decided that he was going
to learn to play the guitar.
And I was talking to him about it,
and I said, well, if you're going to learn
to play the guitar, it's a
really good idea to get lessons,
because you just
go a lot faster if you get lessons.
And he said, oh, no, I
don't want to take lessons.
I was like, OK. And I said, well,
why don't you want to take lessons?
He said, because I don't want
to learn how to read music.
And this is a friend of mine
who's got PhD in chemistry,
so he's not an idiot,
although he's been quite
idiotic about this.
And I said, well, why don't you
want to learn music notation?
Yeah, well, you pick it up really easily.
And he said, oh, yeah, but Paul
McCartney doesn't read music.
And I took about half
a second, and I said,
yeah, but there's a big point here.
You're not Paul McCartney.
You're not a genius. Paul McCartney
is literally the most successful musician
who has ever lived by a
bunch of different measures.
He's not the person you should be
comparing yourself to
when you start to learn
the guitar. Right? That is
just a recipe for misery.